# **Travis Manship**

Email: <a href="mailto:tmansdev@gmail.com">tmansdev@gmail.com</a>

Phone: (325) 440-9462

#### **Profile:**

Experienced, Responsible and Self-motivated Full Stack engineer

Always focusing on business value and customer success, and love to work with team.

Based on good fundamental IT knowledge and experienced general tech stacks like Golang, Node.js, React and Vue etc, I have implemented many web/mobile/application products.

My expertise includes API design, implement and integration.

I'm also interested in blockchain area and I participated and contributed on several freelancer projects as web3/smart contract developer.

#### Backend:

- Golang
- Node.js/Express/Strapi
- Python/FastAPI
- Php/Laravel
- Java/J2EE/Spring/Spring Boot
- C++/C#
- Ruby on Rails
- Postgres/Mysql/Oracle/MSSQL/Mongo/Redis

#### Frontend:

- React.js/Redux/React-Native/Next.js
- Vue.js 2/3, Nuxt
- Bootstrap, Material UI, Tailwind
- Javascript/Typescript

### Blockchain:

- Solidity, hardhat, truffle, web3, dex on Evm blockchain
- Rust, spl, anchor, metaplex on Solana blockchain
- Cadence on flow blockchain

### Other:

- Github/Gitlab/Bitbucket
- AWS/GCP/IBM Cloud/Azure
- Docker/Kubernates/Jenkins/CircleCI
- Prometheus/Grafana
- Jira/Monday/Asana

### Languages:

English, Chinese

## **Education:**

• 2008 – 2012 Beijing Institute of Technology, Computer Science(Bachelor's Degree)

### **Employment History:**

## Cratus Technology

Full Stack engineer 2020.4-2023.3

- Worked on several projects to develop cloud based IoT solution
- Designed the entire architecture and communication protocol, and implemented the backend and frontend for Cloud system(Golang, React/Redux, InfluxDB, AWS, Postgres)
- Implemented the backend using Node.js/Python and the frontend using React and D3 for End-User IoT system(React/Redux/Typescript, Node.js)
- Ensured smooth operation of both projects and ensured they met the company's standards and customer needs
- Test and fix issues/bugs, and added logging/reporting/monitoring features

#### Clarus R&D

Senior Golang Engineer

2017.3-2020.3

- Led the development of a highly successful hotel/flight reservation system that exceeded customer expectations and drove growth.(Golang, React, Redux, Azure, Postgres)
- Designed and executed business logic, backend APIs, and security features for a ticket reservation system and Tax credit service, resulting in improved security and reliability.(Golang, Microservice, Postgres)
- Created an intuitive frontend for a hotel/flight reservation system and tax credit service that improved user experience and increased customer satisfaction.(React/Redux/Vue/Vuex)
- Developed and conducted comprehensive testing to ensure high-quality delivery of backend logic and React components.(React, Typescript, Storyboard)

### **Neusis**

Web/Mobile Developer

2012.4-2017.2

- Using Golang and Node.js, Built robust and scalable backend systems, integrating Restful/GraphQL APIs and third-party APIs, to enhance functionality and support business growth
- Implementation/Bug fixing of CRM (J2EE Spring)
- Designed whole architecture and database, and implemented ETL solution(Java, Swing)
- Maintained/Improved Ruby on Rails backend API service.
- Delivered innovative web-based solutions that increased efficiency and streamline processes for clients, utilizing React.js, Vue.js, and Angular 1/2.
- Designed and launched mobile apps that improved user experience and engagement, using React Native.
- ERP System implementation using C# API2 and React.js